CHUCK C.WILLIAMS, JR.

ORMOND BEACH, FL · 720.924.6125 · CHUCK@SCREENSCHOLAR.COM

Patented software developer. Terrestrial radio show & podcast co-host. Public speaker. Crypto-freedom activist.

Evolved, empathic problem solving involves clear assessment of reality, honest & transparent communications, and the capability to push through to results. I make this work my art.

Listed as inventor of 2 patents (Shutterfly's Photobook Application, and Level3's Dynamic Prompt System). History with visual design and User Experience (UX) oriented strategies and implementations. Current favorite technologies now include React/Redux/Firebase, AngularJS, NodeJS, MongoDB and the related ecosystem of build and dependency management tools (Webpack, Jest, Gulp, Grunt, Bower, etc.).

Contributed to projects affecting the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI which oversees the FBI & CIA). Facilitated projects with National Geographic, Discovery, and The Learning Channels, Qwest and Level 3 Communications. Authored code for FedEx's Print Online Application allowing customers to upload and retrieve documents from FedEx Office Locations.

Strengths include excellent business communications skills, measurable productivity, strategic planning, project direction, team management, and elegant problem solving in the realms of application code, systems architecture, and data management. Also heavy advocate for purposeful living, empathy, meditation, and radical transparency.

Twenty-consecutive-year history with ECMAScript (JavaScript & ActionScript), HTML, & CSS. Also competent with React, AngularJS, NodeJS, PHP, ColdFusion, MySQL, MSSQL, OracleSQL, Grunt, Adobe Fireworks, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, 3D Studio MAX, Ableton Live, and Audio Mixing Board technology. Familiar with design patterns, client relations & presentations, and digital innovation and transformation strategies.

EXPERIENCE

TECH LEAD / DEVOPS / AUTOMATION, PROCESS, & UX FULL STACK DEVELOPER

EQUA START, LLC: DENVER, COLORADO & REMOTE

I teamed up with Equa to build a new and innovative way of managing agreements, and owning entities (like LLC's and Legal Trusts). I bring value to the team by analyzing, developing, and managing client service processes, developing automation, authoring code, designing UX flows, and building application interfaces and integrations in partnership with the client success team, and orchestrate that work in concert with multiple development teams. Reporting directly to the COO, I also monitor and guide the Equa application development process, and how the application flows directly integrate into client service processes. I then target areas of high-friction for automation improvements. I also conduct Microsoft Platform DevOps, User Administration, and Email/Domain Management, as secondary objectives to making ownership and value transfers in orginazational entities easy with the Equa Agreements Platform.

RADIO & PODCAST SHOW CO-HOST

THE CRYPTO SHOW: GLOBAL & REMOTE

Co-hosting The Crypto Show, broadcasting on Bloomberg AM Radio in 5 cities, Let's talk bitcoin, and youtube.com.

- Selecting & coordinating guests & topics.
- Preparing, Researching, and Interviewing guests on live & prerecorded broadcasts.
- Promoting & Advertising for sponsors including <u>The Dash Masternode Network</u>, <u>Edge Wallet</u>, and <u>Anarchapulco</u>.

December 2018 - Present

July 2018 - Present

TECHNICAL & PRODUCT ADVOCATE / ADVISOR / UI/UX DEVELOPER / PUBLIC SPEAKER / CRYPTO-ACTIVIST

SELF EMPLOYED: GLOBAL

Accepting speaking engagements, offering consultation & full-stack development in the areas of Dash:digital cash, the cryptocurrency industry, web & mobile app interaction, and general software development. Offering perspectives, technical consulting, and solutions about whether, why, & how the blockchain should or should not be used for your next business project.

- "What is Evolution?" ~ Dash Conference:London, October 2017
- "What is Dash contributing to the Cannabis Economy?" ~ CannMed:UCLA Campus, December 2018
- "DASH-ing to FREEDOM!" ~ Anarchapulco: Acapulco, February 2018
- Candidate for Dash Masternode Trust Protector December, 2017 (Results)

USER INTERFACE & USER EXPERIENCE TECHNICAL LEAD

DASH CORE GROUP, INC: PHOENIX, ARIZONA & REMOTE

Spokesperson, project management, code authorship, hiring & managing empathic designers & developers.

- Represented Dash Cryptocurrency at conferences, events, and expos connecting business leaders with the right technical or business teams within Dash Core Group.
- Acted as liaison between technical dev team & public facing contractors to a globally remote decentralized, distributed team of architects, developers, designers, and project managers
- Implemented website updates & build fixes upon dash.org.
- Authored NodeJs, ReactJS, AngularJS, SASS, SCSS/CSS3, BootStrap, and HTML/Jade code

USER EXPERIENCE & INTERFACE LEAD / SCRUM MASTER

PLAYERLYNC, LLC: DENVER, COLORADO

Led the development team in all things UI/UX for the online Administrative tools (PLUI Admin) and enduser consumers (WebLync) that manage and deliver the PlayerLync ecosystem of content management.

- Architected and executed the Web based administrative tool for PlayerLync's ecosystem within 9 months of beginning employment.
- Acted as technical decision maker for new components, interfaces, and UI technologies for client implementations of the PlayerLync ecosystem for clients such as Chipotle, the Denver Broncos, PF Chang's, and at least a hundred other wellknown brand names.
- Leading & Training the development team in SCRUM practices, including facilitating retrospectives, calculating and discussing team metrics, coaching executive leadership, and product managers on producing value from the team.
- Authoring PHP, AngularJS, SASS, SCSS/CSS3, jQuery, BootStrap, and HTML/Jade code.

SENIOR PROGRAMMER / ANALYST - INTERNET

OPPENHEIMERFUNDS, INC: ENGLEWOOD, COLORADO (ACQUIRED BY <u>INVESCO</u>)

Reported directly to the Assistant Vice President of the Corporate Technology Group and lead the development team in all things UI/UX. Work included addressing hot production issues, forwardthinking longterm project planning & review, and delivering rich interfaces and visualizations for investors and investment brokers. Authored Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, SASS, SCSS/CSS3, jQuery, Foundation, & HTML/HAML code.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

LEVEL 3 COMMUNICATIONS: BROOMFIELD, COLORADO (ACQUIRED BY <u>CENTURYLINK</u>)

Acted as a Lead UI Architect for implementations on utility oriented, self-service, customer facing web presences. Applied as inventor for my 2nd Patent. Delivered applications with AngularJS, Java, JSP, JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone, Flex, ActionScript, & Oracle SQL.

January 2017 - June 2018

January 2015 - June 2017

September 2013 - December 2014

September 2011 - September 2013

PRACTICE LEAD / SOFTWARE ARCHITECT / SENIOR SALES ENGINEERING CONSULTANT

EFFECTIVE UI, INC: DENVER, COLORADO (ACQUIRED BY **OGILVY**)

Authored code & led development projects from design through to delivery for many Fortune 500 Organizations. Lead development team and became a named inventor of patent #12/969,808. Also facilitated "discovery workshops" and focused on developing comprehensive strategies. Authored countless lines of Actionscript, Coldfusion, Flex, FlexUnit, RobotLegs, JavaScript, Java, JSP, Oracle SQL, HTML & CSS.

June 2006 - May 2008 **SOLUTIONS LEADER**

NYK LOGISTICS, AMERICAS: MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE

April 2004 - June 2006 **SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST**

MIND OVER DATA, LLC: MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE

CREATIVE SERVICES DEPARTMENT & MULTIMEDIA DEVELOPMENT MANAGER April 2002 - April 2004

THE DATA COMPANY, LLC: MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE

PRODUCTION DESIGNER - WEB SPECIALIST November 2000 - April 2002

PRISMA INTERNATIONAL: MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA

MULTIMEDIA DEVELOPER May 1998 - November 2000

SELF-EMPLOYED: MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA

EDUCATION

ACADEMY COLLEGE August 1997 - May 1999

BLOOMINGTON, MINNESOTA: ASSOCIATE OF APPLIED SCIENCE

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- Continuous Learning Courses on <u>Udemy</u>, <u>CodeCademy</u>, <u>Egghead.io</u>.
- Rally Agile Practices Training: April 2011
- Macromedia Certified ColdFusion Developer Certification 2004
- Macromedia Flash Advanced Developer Certification 2002

May 2008 – April 2011

October 1976 - Present

SKILLS

PLATFORMS & SUITES



PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

























WORKFLOW

- ✓ Mobile-First, Responsive Design
- Cross Browser Testing & Debugging
- Cross Functional Teams
- ✓ Agile Development & Scrum
- ✓ Process Analysis & Design
- ✓ Workflow & Process Automation

SOFT

- ✓ Team Management, Goal Setting, Review, & Critique
- ✓ Facilitation of Group Decision-making
- ✓ Product Ownership, & Management
- ✓ Task Definition, Tracking, Follow-through, and improvement
- ✓ Public Speaking & Communications
- ✓ Sales Engineering, Requirements Gathering
- ✓ Problem Diagnosis & Creative Solution Option Generation